American Association for Labor Legislation Records on Microfilm 5001 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Correspondence: 1926, Jan 27 - 1926, June 18. (Reel 33)
  Correspondence of this period centers on the AALL's announcement (2/19/26) that its federal compensation bill for longshoremen had been introduced in the House and would be referred to as the Cummins-Graham Bill. William Green wrote (3/2/26) that the American Federation of Labor had informed Anthony Chlopek that all possible support would be given to this bill. Eleanor Roosevelt wrote (3/4/25) in response to an AALL form letter to the membership on this question that she was writing to the Democratic members of the House and Senate Judiciary Committee, urging support for the bill. Chlopek informed John Andrews (5/1/26) that his efforts on behalf of the International Longshoremen's Association (ILA) were much appreciated. Other areas of the Association's work were not forgotten. In early February Andrews traveled to Washington to lobby for the passage of the Fitzgerald Workmen's Compensation Bill and to consult with Congressman Fitzgerald. In March he reported to J. R. Haynes his meetings with Herbert Hoover and Scott Turner regarding his work on a mine safety bill. A New York Times editorial, dated May 8, praising the AALL's advocacy of coal dusting for coal mine safety, was the basis for yet another attempt by Andrews to raise funds for the Association.
- Correspondence: 1926, June 19 - 1927, Mar 5., 1926-1927 (Reel 34)
  The progress of the Graham-Cummins bill was of continuing interest. Congressman Graham gave John Andrews his version of the reason why the bill never was called out of committee in the House, although it did pass the Senate. From August through December, Andrews kept up a running correspondence with Charles Verrill and Anthony Chlopek on amendments to the Graham-Cummins bill that might enable it to pass at the next session. In late November Thomas Chadbourne made an unusual pledge to the Association, promising to give $10,000 a year for the next three years if Andrews could raise $15,000. The money was intended especially to wipe the "black spots" off the compensation map. (The AALL Review periodically published a map showing workmen's compensation legislation's spread by state. Those states without any compensation law at all were shown in solid black, hence "black spots.") Andrews replied to this letter (12/2/26). Programs for 1927 included achieving workmen's compensation laws in those five states still without them, workmen's compensation for longshoremen (Graham-Cummins), and mine safety. John Andrews went frequently to Washington to organize support for the Graham-Cummins bill. The legislation was finally passed on March 4, 1927. Throughout March, letters were received regretting the effect of the American Association for Old Age Security (Epstein's new organiza-tion, AAOAS) on the American Association for Labor Legislation. Most officers of the new association were AALL members and many felt that they had been misled by Epstein in regard to John Andrews' support for the AAOAS.
- Correspondence: 1927, Mar 7 - Oct 31. (Reel 35)
  Concerned over the problem of two national organizations dedicated to very similar purposes, Paul H. Douglas and Ethelbert Talbot tried to arrange a merger of the AALL and the AAOAS, After much correspondence, this effort was to result in failure. Andrews was very busy trying to raise funds to match the Chadbourne pledge. He also began an attack on the lack of workmen's compensation legislation in Florida with a series of letters to local politicians and local AALL members. A blow to the Association's mine safety campaign came when J. R. Haynes informed Andrews (8/2/27) that he would have to discontinue his financial support of the AALL in order to concentrate on a public ownership plan in Los Angeles. Andrews sought funding from the United Mine Workers. A letter in the fall from John L. Lewis (10/14/27) in-formed the Association that the request would go before the national executive board of the union. Work with E. A. Holbrook on mine safety standards was carried on through September and October.
- Correspondence: 1927, Nov 1 - 1928, Mar 18., 1927-1928 (Reel 36)
  The question of a merger with the AAOAS, the problems of administering workmen's compensation for longshoremen, and the reintroduction of the bill to provide workmen's compensation in the District of Columbia were the Association's priority concerns in those months. Miles Dawson described to Andrews (11/22/27) Abraham Epstein's willingness to merge if the AALL would finance the new organization. Andrews was not enthusiastic about the suggestion, and in a letter to Frank Hering of the Eagles (1/4/28) detailed his reasons for avoiding the merger. The conflict with the Epstein organization continued to cause difficulties, as reflected in a letter from Florence Kelley (3/15/28) that charged the AALL with a lack of depth.
- Correspondence: 1928, Mar 19 - 1928, Sept 30. (Reel 37)
  The passage of the Fitzgerald Bill providing workmen's compensation for private employees in the District of Columbia was the highlight of the spring and summer. Merger of the AALL and the AAOAS was still advocated by Paul Douglass and by I. M. Rubinow and Stephen Wise, who were longtime advisers of Andrews. Before the Fitzgerald Bill was enacted, Margaret Hobbs James had succeeded to the position of AALL lobbyist. Andrews congratulated her on the bill's enactment (5/14/28) and the following day assigned her to work on the Jones Bill for the vocational rehabilitation of industrial cripples. The Ribnik vs. McBride decision of the Supreme Court upset the AALL's efforts to regulate private fee-charging employment agencies. There is correspondence with Robert Wagner which leads to his intro-duction in Congress of an AALL-drafted bill providing for public em-ployment bureaus. Andrews wrote Sophy Sanger (7/18/28) that he would be attending some of the international social workers conferences in Paris in July, and hoped to spend some time after that in Britain gathering material on British labor law administration. On his return in September, he wrote to Frank Hering of the Eagles, proposing that they undertake a joint study of old age pension systems in New York State.
- Correspondence: 1928, Oct 1 - 1929, Feb 5., 1928-1929 (Reel 38)
  Workmen's compensation became an increasing concern of the Asso-ciation. John Andrews queried Felix Frankfurter and others about the possibility of compensation for railroad workers. Frankfurter's reply (10/30/28) did not favor a federal program, but suggested individual state legislation. Andrews was always keenly interested in national politics and supported Al Smith against Herbert Hoover. In November, after Smith's defeat, he wrote Solon De Leon that he was terribly disappointed, "Our vaunted religious liberty is but a bubble that has been pricked." Turning his attention to New York State, he wrote the then Governor-elect, Franklin D. Roosevelt, suggesting that he include occupational disease compensation and regulation of fee-charging private employment agencies in his 1929 message to the legislature. Governor Roosevelt replied that he thought the AALL's proposal of blanket coverage for occupational diseases was reasonable, and that he did not anticipate much objection to the proposals. Andrews wrote to Felix Frankfurter again, this time to inquire whether Frankfurter had written a minimum wage bill that would meet the constitutional objections. Frankfurter replied (12/20/28) that he felt that he and B. V. Cohen had, but that correspondence was too cumbersome a medium for discussion; Mr. Cohen would come to confer with Mr. Andrews. The program for 1929 was planned to include the social cost of accidents, sickness and old age insurance, unemployment, labor law administration and workmen's compensation for the new industrial South. A form letter (1/23/29) urged that members write in support of the vocational rehabilitation bill, the Jones Property Reserve Bill and the Wagner Bill (in earlier years known as the Kenyon-Nolan Bill) for adequate public employment bureaus. Margaret James Hobbs wrote (2/4/29) that she was discouraged in her work for the passage of the vocational rehabilitation bill, and expressed hope that Andrews would come to Washington to organize support for it.
- Correspondence: 1929, Feb 6 - 1930, Jan 6. (Reel 39)
  The year 1929 was dominated by the Association's attempt to institute workmen's compensation in the few southern states without it. The curtailment of contributions made the financial conditions even more critical than usual. Andrews was hard-pressed to match the Chadbourne pledge. The AALL's first mid-year annual meeting was organized in March. In May, and throughout the year, Andrews corresponded with John R. Commons and others concerning a very extensive study by the Association of labor law administration in the United States. Later that month Frances Perkins appointed Andrews to the Governor's Commission on Unemployment Problems in New York State. Andrews' attacks on a new appointee to the United States Employees Compensation Commission upset Fiorello La Guardia, who wrote to Andrews that the man in question "...may not have a college degree but he does have a heart." (6/11/29) The Association's relationship with the International Longshore-men's Association suffered when the new president, Joseph Ryan, was displeased by Andrews' actions in the union's behalf (6/20/29). Congressman G. W. Norris wrote Andrews (6/22/29) that Ryan informed him that the Longshoremen were not behind the legislation that Andrews had requested Norris to introduce. William Doak wrote (7/5/29) in regard to compensation for railroad workers that some of the men were too strongly opposed to it for the union to favor such legislation. The Andrews' enjoyed a long working trip across the country in the summer. During most of the fall, Andrews worked on unemployment prob-lems. In a December letter, John Fitch (12/6/29) reported that Labor News had suggested that the AALL be asked to draft a bill to create a federal unemployment insurance system, and that if the Association did not do so, a new national organization would be formed to push such legislation. In January John Andrews and AALL staff member Cornelius Cochrane traveled in the South to generate support for workmen's compensation legislation.
- Correspondence: 1929, Feb 6 - 1930, Jan 6. (continued), 1929-1930 (Reel 40)
  The year 1929 was dominated by the Association's attempt to insti-tute workmen's compensation in the few southern states without it. The curtailment of contributions made the financial conditions even more critical than usual. Andrews was hard-pressed to match the Chadbourne pledge. The AALL's first mid-year annual meeting was organized in March. In May, and throughout the year, Andrews corresponded with John R. Commons and others concerning a very extensive study by the Association of labor law administration in the United States. Later that month Frances Perkins appointed Andrews to the Governor's Commission on Unemployment Problems in New York State. Andrews' attacks on a new appointee to the United States Employees Compensation Commission upset Fiorello La Guardia, who wrote to Andrews that the man in question "...may not have a college degree but he does have a heart." (6/11/29) The Association's relationship with the International Longshore-men's Association suffered when the new president, Joseph Ryan, was displeased by Andrews' actions in the union's behalf (6/20/29). Congressman G. W. Norris wrote Andrews (6/22/29) that Ryan informed him that the Longshoremen were not behind the legislation that Andrews had requested Norris to introduce. William Doak wrote (7/5/29) in regard to compensation for railroad workers that some of the men were too strongly opposed to it for the union to favor such legislation. The Andrews' enjoyed a long working trip across the country in the summer. During most of the fall, Andrews worked on unemployment prob-lems. In a December letter, John Fitch (12/6/29) reported that Labor News had suggested that the AALL be asked to draft a bill to create a federal unemployment insurance system, and that if the Association did not do so, a new national organization would be formed to push such legislation. In January John Andrews and AALL staff member Cornelius Cochrane traveled in the South to generate support for workmen's compensation legislation.
- Correspondence: 1930, Jan 7 - May 31. (Reel 41)
  John Andrews and some AALL staff members remained in the South, particularly in Florida and South Carolina, organizing support for workmen's compensation. Ida Tarbell requested background information (1/28/30) for an article on vocational rehabilitation. The Association's work in New York State was largely in the form of lobbying for control of fee-charging employment agencies. Andrews was discouraged by the long fight against such agencies and wrote Joseph Chamberlain (3/13/30) that if AALL could not get that bill passed this year, it might just as well give it up. Fred Wilcox, Chairman of the New York State Committee on Unemployment Problems, sent Andrews a copy of the committee's report (3/25/30). Financial conditions continued to create severe constraint on the Association's activity, and Thomas Chadbourne informed the Association (4/7/30) that he would not be able to renew his annual gift of $10,000. A mid-year meeting was held in conjunction with the National Con-ference of Social Work. The AALL's program included workmen's compensation, social insurance, old age pensions and unemployment remedies. April through June saw concentrated work on the unemployment relief bills that Robert Wagner had introduced. Wagner informed Andrews (5/28/30) that these bills should be passed before the Association's unemployment insurance bill was introduced.
- Correspondence: 1930 June 1 - Nov 12., 1931 (Reel 42)
  Unemployment problems and their solution dominated the activities of the summer and fall of 1930. Governor Roosevelt asked Andrews (9/13/30) to arrange a meeting with Sir William Beveridge. Weeks later the Association launched a massive survey of unemployment across the nation. Joseph Chamberlain's letter to Andrews (9/27/30) encloses a draft of the unemployment insurance bill. Subsequent letters dis-cuss amendments and reactions to the draft. A form letter from the AALL to the nation's governors announced a national conference on unemployment in conjunction with that year's annual meeting of the Association.
- Correspondence: 1930, Nov 13 - 1931, Feb 5. (Reel 43)
  The Association continued to devote its work in November and December to the ever increasing problems of unemployment, with a renewed interest in public works projects to reduce the ranks of the jobless. John Andrews, John Fitch, Grace Coyle, Mary Drier, Rose Schneiderman, and many others formed a committee to push unemployment insurance in the New York State legislature under the auspices of the AALL. Governor Roosevelt requested John Andrews' concrete proposals to fight unemployment (12/29/30). The new year brought the involvement of even more people in the Association's plans for unemployment insurance. Paul Raushenbush wrote from Wisconsin that he and Elizabeth Brandeis had ideas about the unemployment problem and wished to cooperate with the AALL. His letter (1/8/31) began many years of correspondence with Andrews on this subject, ending only with Andrews' death. Under discussion was the Association's "American Plan for Unemployment Insurance," a plan that featured no contribution to the fund on the part of the employees. William Doak, newly appointed United States Secretary of Labor, accepted the vice-presidency of the AALL on January 17, and a few weeks later (2/2/31) resigned because of the Association's advocacy of the Wagner employment bills.
- Correspondence: 1931, Feb 6 - June 2. (Reel 44)
  The Association's activities in the spring of 1931 were evenly distributed between unemployment relief and workmen's compensation for the southern states still without it. Activities in New York State centered on the recently formed Conference for Unemployment Insurance Legislation. John Fitch's letter from the conference to the parent AALL (3/10/31) lists the officers of the conference. Roosevelt wrote to Andrews (3/19/31), asking him to serve on a commission to solve the problem of inadequate medical aid for compensation cases. Later, Andrews wrote Roosevelt, urging that he not sign the bill authorizing private corporations to sell unemployment insurance. Andrews was in Florida in May working for workmen's compensa-tion.
- Correspondence: 1931, June 3 - Nov 10. (Reel 45)
  The familiar themes of unemployment prevention, workmen's compensation for the South and the need of the AALL for financial support recur throughout this period. A form letter sent in early June (6/4/31) indicated that at the mid-year meeting which would be held in Minneapolis, the chief topic was to be the prevention of unemployment. In July a telegram to the AALL office from John Andrews (7/15/31) indicated that he was working in North Carolina on workmen's compensation legislation. Later, Andrews wrote Ernest Draper (8/31/31) that Cochrane was still working in the South, particularly in South Carolina. The Executive Secretary's correspondence with John R. Commons (8/14/31) and a letter from Paul Raushenbush discuss the AALL's sponsorship of an education program in Wisconsin on unemployment insurance, financed primarily by Raushenbush and Elizabeth Brandeis. In September (9/19/31) the program, called the Wisconsin Commission for Unemployment Reserve Legislation, accelerated.
- Correspondence: 1931, Nov 11 - 1932, Mar 3., 1931-1932 (Reel 46)
  Public works programs were urged simultaneously with the establishment of unemployment reserves. December 1931 and early 1932 correspondence with Arthur J. Altmeyer, Thomas Parkinson and Robert M. LaFollette Jr. included these subjects. Edwin E. Witte wrote John Andrews (1/16/32), giving the AALL credit for the Wisconsin unemployment insurance bill's passage and praising Andrews personally for his contribution. In February, Joseph Chamberlain and Andrews drafted legislation that would empower the United States Employees Compensation Commission to issue safety orders.
- Correspondence: 1932, Mar 6 - Sept 15. (Reel 47)
  In early March and April the Croweel vs. Benson decision evoked comments from Edwin E. Witte (3/15/32), Joseph Chamberlain (3/7/32), Arthur J. Altmeyer (3/29/32) and Walter F. Dodd (4/11/32). The fight to stem the flood of unemployment continued. Arthur J. Altmeyer (3/19/32) and Paul Raushenbush (3/11/32) wrote concerning unemployment insurance and reserves. The AALL backed the policy on the change in name of the New York Conference for Unemployment Insurance Legislation to the New York Conference for Unemployment Reserves Legislation (3/21/32). Andrews wrote Anna Bogue, secretary to Mrs. Willard Straight Elmhurst, a heavy contributor, that he was attempting to set up effective state commissions on unemployment reserve legislation in Michigan and Pennsylvania (4/19/32). Robert F. Wagner congratulated Andrews (4/25/32) on the favorable report that the United States House of Representatives Commerce Com-mittee gave on the unemployment exchange bill. Wagner also stated that he had appreciated Andrews' assistance when the fight reached the floor. Roosevelt wrote to Andrews (5/25/32), inviting him to continue to serve on a commission to study the medical and hospital problems of workmen's compensation. In August William Green wrote to Andrews (8/12/32), welcoming his aid in regard to unemployment insurance.
- Correspondence: 1932, Sept 16 - 1933, Jan 31., 1932-1933 (Reel 48)
  During this period, Andrews and the Association were occupied primarily with unemployment relief. Andrews wrote Paul Raushenbush (10/4/32) about the amount of time the AALL had spent in working out a formula that would "save face" for gubernatorial candidate Lehman and reverse his position on unemployment reserves. A letter to Ernest Draper (11/10/32) deals with the National Committee on Unemployment Reserves, a satellite of the AALL. The problem of how to invest unemployment reserve monies also received wide attention. Mary E. Drier, Executive Secretary of the New York Conference on Unemployment Reserves Legislation, wrote to Irene Osgood Andrews (1/2/33), reminding her that when Lehman spoke on unemployment insurance, they must write and thank him for his leadership. In mid-January form letters were sent to all Democratic governors, calling on them to honor the Democratic platform supporting state legislation for unemployment insurance.
- Correspondence: 1933, Feb 1 - Aug 2. (Reel 49)
  The program for 1933 included a national system of public employment offices, federal encouragement of state unemployment reserves, and accident compensation for railroad and interstate workers. The Association was in such need of funds and office space that John Andrews offered (3/13/33) to sell the AALL collection of early literature on workmen's compensation to John P. Troxell at Duke University. The American Association for Old Age Pensions changed its name to the American Association for Social Security (AASS), also changing its focus, and arousing much comment. The AASS released its standards for unemployment insurance on July 22. Discussion on the merits of these standards continued through December in the AALL's correspondence. Elizabeth Brandeis, Frances Perkins, and John A. Fitch were among those who contributed their opinions.
- Correspondence: 1933, Aug 3 - 1934, Feb 11., 1933-1934 (Reel 50)
  Unemployment reserves and social security were still the chief programs of the organization. Personality factors were prominent in disputes. In August Mary Drier wrote to warn Andrews (8/7/33) that they must keep Abraham Epstein out of the New York State fight for unemployment insurance. Dorothy Douglas resigned from the executive committee (11/4/33) because she felt its attitude toward unemployment insurance had been equivocal. Miles M. Dawson wrote Andrews (12/20/33) that he wished to cooperate with the AALL because he had had a falling out with Epstein. The AALL program for 1934 included sponsorship of legislation providing unemployment reserves, amendment of workmen's compensation, and public employment offices. In February Edwin E. Witte wrote to Andrews (2/9/34), advising him that unemployment insurance was winning support for Epstein and the AASS. Wittee felt the AALL should move quickly as "the champion of the rights of organized labor," to counter the swing.
- Correspondence: 1934, Feb 12 - July 31. (Reel 51)